《星际迷航9：起义》
他在那里！抓住他
There he is! Let's get him.
快来啊
Come on.
验证物化序列
Verifying materialization sequence.
在12号雷达上清晰显像
Bring up resolution on radar unit 12.
- 七区呼叫指挥部 - 请讲
- Area 7 to Command. - Go ahead.
我们这边需要增添人手 长官
We could use another survey team out here, sir.
基地呼叫麦康利少尉和吉儿少尉
Base to Ensign McCauley and Ensign Gilles.
请前往第七区 协助土壤勘探组
Please report to Area 7 and assist the edaphology team.
收到指令
Acknowledged.
把资料输入二级处理器
Transferring anthropometric data files to secondary processor.
- 人种研究表明97%… - 星球生态分析…
- Ethnographic studies indicate 97%… - The ecological analysis…
还在比对中…
Still working on correlating that unidentified…
对比语言分析已完成 长官
The comparative linguistic analysis is complete, sir.
多尔蒂将军正等它呢 传到飞船上去
Admiral Dougherty is waiting for this. Transmit it to the ship.
警报！第十二区！
Alert! Area 12!
- 那个机器人失去控制了 - 报告情况
- The android, he's out of control. - Report.
他冲着村子里去了 我们正试着拦住他
He's headed toward the village. We're trying to stop him.
在那边！
Over there!
放大
Magnify.
先别开枪
Hold your fire.
怎么回事？出什么事了？
What is it? What's happening?
基地呼叫数据
Base to Commander Data.
修改微型液压分配
Rerouting micro-hydraulic power distribution.
- 调节热量超负荷 - 数据 立即向基地汇报！
- Regulating thermal overload. - Data, report to Base immediately!
准备正电子矩阵功能 启动二级协议
Transferring positronic matrix functions. Engaging secondary protocol.
他想要拿掉头盔
He's trying to remove the headpiece.
所有单位 拦截这个机器人
All field units, intercept the android.
阿添 阿添 没事了
Artim, Artim, it's all right.
进屋去 快点儿
Get inside. Now.
快找掩护 大伙快进屋 快点儿 赶快回去！
Find shelter. Everyone, get inside. Now. Back to your homes! Move it!
快！回家去！
Now! Move!
二级协议启动
Secondary protocol is active.
- 他们看见他了 - 拦住他！快点儿！
- They can see him. - Stop him! Now!
数据中校 快点退后 这是命令！重复 赶快退后！
Commander Data, stand down. That's an order! I repeat, stand down!
他们是什么人？
Who are they?
这是一颗M级星球 人口总数三亿
It's an M-Class planet. Population, 300 million.
- 再说一遍问候语？- 尤金且佛儿
- Say the greeting again. - Yew-cheen chef-faw.
「金」音和「佛」两个字要重读
Emphasis on the "cheen" and the "faw."
要么换件制服要么换个脖子
You either need a new uniform or a new neck.
我上军校后领子尺寸就没变过
My collar size is exactly as it was at the academy.
看得出来
Of course it is.
客人们已经到了
Our guests have arrived.
他们在大吃餐桌上的装饰花呢
They are eating the floral arrangements on the banquet tables.
我想他们饭前大概不喝鸡尾酒
I guess they don't believe in cocktails before dinner.
天啊！他们是素食者？资料上没写？
Oh, my God! Are they vegetarian? That's not in there.
也许我们该叫厨师赶做一份酸辣酱油
Perhaps we should have the chef whip up a light balsamic vinaigrette,
浇在菊花上会非差好吃
something that goes well with chrysanthemums.
- 舰桥呼叫船长 - 说吧 少尉
- Bridge to Captain Picard. - Go ahead, Ensign.
指挥部问我们何时抵达哥伦星系
Command wants to know our ETA at the Goren system.
哥伦星系？
The Goren system?
他们要我们去调解领空纠纷
They need us to mediate some territorial dispute.
不 不
No, no.
我们不能耽误去汉伦二号星的考古勘察
We can't delay the archeological expedition to Hanoran II.
不然就会赶上季风期
That'll put us right in the middle of the monsoon season.
- 船长 - 谢谢
- Captain. - Thank you.
外交团正忙着和自治领谈判
The diplomatic corps is busy with Dominion negotiations.
哦对 所以就派我们去做和事佬
Yes. So they need us to put out one more brush fire.
谁还会记得我们的专长是去探险？
Can anyone remember when we used to be explorers?
- 第十层 - 尤金且佛儿
- Deck 10. - Yew-cheen chef-faw.
记着 他们的科技远远没有我们先进
Remember, they have a significantly less advanced technology than ours.
他们去年才发明出曲翘推进器
They only achieved warp drive last year.
联邦这么快就决定让他们成为保护国
And the Federation Council decided to make them a protectorate so quickly.
鉴于失去了博格人和自治领
In view of our losses to the Borg and the Dominion,
所以议会的委员们觉得我们该多找些盟友
the Council feels we need all the allies we can get these days.
船长到
Captain on deck.
你得邀请古莎亲王跳支舞
You'll be expected to dance with the Regent Cuzar.
- 她会跳曼波舞吗？- 真幽默
- Can she mambo? - Very funny.
船长以前是舞林高手
The Captain used to cut quite a rug.
拉弗吉呼叫皮卡特
La Forge to Picard.
船长 我有事情要汇报
Captain, I need to talk to you before the reception.
- 船长 医生 - 亲爱的胡夫先生！
- Captain. Doctor. - Mr. Worf!
- 胡夫 - 你跑这儿来干什么？
- Worf. - What the hell are you doing here?
- 本来我是在在曼扎检查新的防卫设施… - 稍等一会 佐迪
- I was at the Manzar colony… - He's a little late, Geordi.
- 可以等吗？- 不行
- Can it wait? - I don't think so.
哦对不起 告诉他我已经来了
Excuse me. Tell him that I'm already here,
等他来了我们再谈 胡夫先生 我对…
and I'll talk to him when he arrives. Mr. Worf, I have…
佐迪 船长请你上这儿来
Geordi, the Captain would like you to come up here.
告诉他我们收到了多尔蒂上将的讯息 跟数据有关
Tell him we've received a communiqué from Admiral Dougherty. It's about Data.
尤金且佛儿 古莎亲王 欢迎莅临企业号
Yew-cheen chef-faw, Regent Cuzar. Welcome aboard the Enterprise.
皮卡特船长
Captain Picard,
请允许我用我国人民的仪式欢迎你
may I welcome you in the time- honored tradition of my people?
我们很荣幸能被庞大的联邦家族所接纳
We are so honored to be accepted within the great Federation family.
- 相信稍后您会赏脸和我跳支舞的 - 乐意之至
- We have a dance later, I believe. - I look forward to it.
- 顾问 - 很漂亮的珠子
- Counselor. - Nice bead work.
船长 对不起 船长
Captain. Excuse me. Captain.
多尔蒂上将正在441区一艘桑那人的船上
Captain, Admiral Dougherty is aboard a Son'a ship in Sector 441.
- 他想要数据的设计图 - 出了什么事？
- He's requesting Data's schematics. - Is something wrong?
信息上没说
The message doesn't say.
数据该回来了才对
Data should have been back by now.
计划在巴库村庄只观察一星期
They were only scheduled to observe the Ba'ku village for one week.
佐迪 请在休息室帮我接通上将的保密通讯
Geordi, would you set up a secure comm link with the Admiral in the anteroom.
是 长官
Aye, sir.
船长 我叫哈斯
Captain, Hars Adislo.
我们去年在纳尔巴托会议上见过
We met at the Nel Bato Conference last year.
你有没有看过我写的
Did you ever have a chance to read my paper.
关于热离子跨导的论文？
on thermionic transconductance?
我先失陪一下？
Would you excuse me?
他不承认任何星际舰队的通讯协议
He's not acknowledging any Starfleet protocols,
对我们的呼叫也没有反应
not responding to any of our hails.
你认为是什么原因导致了这种行为？
Have you any idea what precipitated this behavior?
不知道 他现在把我们的人扣押在下面
None. Now he's holding our people hostage down there.
企业号两天后就能到你那，将军
Well, the Enterprise could be at your position in two days, Admiral.
这可能不是个好主意
That's probably not a good idea.
你的飞船并不适应这块地区
Your ship hasn't been fitted for this region.
这区的环境相当特别
There are environmental concerns.
怎么个特别法？
What kind of concerns?
我们还没有完全确认它的异常
We haven't fully identified the anomalies yet.
他们把这一带叫做荆棘区
They're calling this whole area the Briar Patch.
我们花了一天时间
Took us a day to reach a location.
才才抵达能够进行通讯的地方
where we could even get a signal to you.
把数据的设计图给我就是了 有情况我再通知你 通讯完毕
Just get me Data's schematics. I'll keep you informed. Dougherty out.
- 他的情绪晶片？- 他根本就没带
- His emotion chip? - He didn't take it with him.
- 把设计图发给将军 - 是 长官
- Send the Admiral Data's schematics. - Aye, sir.
- 什么事？- 少尉 你能去一趟厨房
- Yes, sir? - Ensign, would you report to the galley.
告诉厨师跳过吃鱼这个过程吗？
and tell the chef to skip the fish course?
是 长官
Aye, sir.
尽快而又不失礼的招待完这些客人
I would like our guests to depart as soon as etiquette allows.
我会叫胡夫暂时留下来 先不回深空9号
I'm going to ask Worf to delay his return to DS9 so that he can join us.
我们去哥伦星系的路上 顺便去一趟441区
We're gonna stop by Sector 441 on our way to the Goren system.
- 这两个地点方向完全相反 长官 - 是吗？
- They are in opposite directions, sir. - Are they?
一开始我就不该听你的话建什么隐形掩体
I never should have let you talk me into that duck blind in the first place.
你们的联邦程序是使完成这次任务的
Your Federation procedures have made this mission.
难度增加了十倍
ten times as difficult as it needed to be.
我们的程序是为了避免当地居民
Our procedures were in place to protect the planet's population.
遇到不必要的危险
from unnecessary risk.
当地居民只有600人而已
Planet's population, 600 people.
你想避免不必要的危险 那下次就别带你的机器人
If you want to avoid unnecessary risks, next time, leave your android at home.
舰桥呼叫罗阿佛将军 我们正靠近星球
Bridge to Ahdar Ru'afo. We are approaching the planet.
进入高空轨道
Take us into a high orbit.
躺下吧 将军 姑娘们能让你年轻二十岁
Lie down, Admiral. The girls'll take 20 years off your face.
- 下次再说吧 - 你的自制让我困惑 将军
- Another time, perhaps. - Your self-restraint puzzles me, Admiral.
你一直在拒绝这次任务给你带来的各种好处
You continue to deny yourself every benefit this mission has to offer.
我更愿意等到和联邦的全体人民
I prefer to wait until we can share the benefits.
一起分享这些好处
with all the people of the Federation.
- 报告情况 - 死光枪 来源不明
- Report. - Phaser blast. Unknown origin.
启动防护罩
Raise shields.
- 离开运行轨道 - 光子鱼雷 准备撞击
- Take us out of orbit. - Photon torpedoes. Brace for impact.
- 已经摆脱敌人的追击 长官 - 打开屏幕
- The vessel has broken off pursuit, sir. - Visual contact.
是我们的飞船
That's our ship.
船长 我们马上将会和星际舰队失去联络
Captain, we're about to lose all communications with Starfleet.
你已经拿到所有资料了？
Do you have everything you need from Command?
我已经下载了掩体任务和桑那人所有的资料
I've downloaded all the files on the duck blind mission and the Son'a.
给你两天时间弄清楚
You have two days to become experts.
胡夫 我们的任务是设法安全的抓住数据
Mr. Worf, our job is to come up with a plan to safely capture Data.
我已经让拉弗吉中校设计了这个三相器
I've already had Commander La Forge modify this tricorder.
来控制数据的伺服器
with one of Data's actuation servos.
它的有效范围只有四米 但是能把它关掉
Its operational range is only 4 meters, but it will shut him down.
很高兴你回来 胡夫先生
Good to have you back, Mr. Worf.
速度降到三分之一 出发
Slow to one-third. Take us in.
半个世纪前 他们征服了两个原始部落
Half a century ago, they conquered two primitive races,
塔拉族和艾拉瑞安族
the Tarlac and the Ellora,
吸纳并且奴役他们
and then integrated them into their culture as a labor class.
看这个
Look at this.
桑那人是以生产大量
The Son'a are known to have produced.
可以迷幻心智的毒药而闻名
mass quantities of the narcotic ketracel-white.
据说他们的飞船上装备了
Their ships are rumored to be equipped.
奇托姆协议所禁止的
with isolytic subspace weapons.
同位线子空间武器
outlawed by the Second Khitomer Accord.
我们怎么跟这帮人扯上了关系？
Why would we be involved with these people?
问得好
Good question.
- 你好久没这样了 - 什么？
- You haven't done that in a long time. - What?
- 弄我的脖子 - 我在弄你的脖子吗？
- What you're doing to my neck. - Was I doing something to your neck?
舰桥呼叫胡夫中校
Bridge to Commander Worf.
- 胡夫！- 船长
- Worf! - Captain.
我不知道在深空9号上是怎么规定的
I don't know how they do it on Deep Space Nine,
不过在企业号 我们必须准时向长官报到
but on the Enterprise, we still report for duty on time.
- 对不起 船长 我就来 - 这次就先饶了你
- Sorry, sir. I'm on my way. - We'll skip the court-martial this time.
通讯结束
Picard out.
转矩感应器是什么时候调校的？
When was the last time we aligned the torque sensors?
- 两个月前 长官 - 好像有误差
- Two months ago, sir. - They don't sound right.
传感器确实有误差 可是只有12微米
The torque sensors are out of alignment by 12 microns.
你能听出来？
You could hear that?
我年轻的时侯连3微米误差也听得出来
When I was an ensign, I could detect a three- micron misalignment.
打扰一下 长官 上将所在飞船
Excuse me, sir. The Son'a ship with Admiral Dougherty aboard.
已进入显像范围
has entered tracking range.
整理一下仪容 中校 打开屏幕
Straighten your baldric, Commander. On screen.
船长 我没想到你会来
Captain, I wasn't expecting you.
这件事很重要 我们不能袖手旁观 将军
This is too important for the Enterprise to be on the sidelines, Admiral.
可惜我没有好消息奉告
I wish I had better news.
数据昨天攻击了我们的任务侦察船
Commander Data attacked us in a mission scout ship yesterday.
我和罗阿佛已经决定派出作战小队
Ru'afo and I have decided to send in an assault team.
胡夫队长和我已经在研究可行的战术计划…
Commander Worf and I are working on several tactical plans to see…
你的机器人已经极为危险 船长
Your android has turned dangerously violent, Captain.
我的飞船受到了损失 必须摧毁它
Considerable damage was done to my ship. He must be destroyed.
我知道数据对星际舰队很重要 吉恩·卢克
I know what Data means to Starfleet, Jean-Luc,
可他和巴库人扣押着我们的船员
but our crew is at the mercy of those people on the planet.
如果我们没有办法活捉数据
If our first attempt to capture Data fails,
我会亲手消毁他
I will terminate him.
这是我的责任 我是他船长也是他的朋友
I should be the one to do it. I'm his captain and his friend.
好 给你十二个小时 之后你就得离开荆棘区
All right, you have 12 hours, Captain. Then I want you out of the Briar Patch.
同时 如果你失败了的话
In the meantime, we'll head out to the perimeter.
这件事就交给桑那援军处理
to call for Son'a reinforcements in case you fail.
- 明白 - 祝你好运 船长 通讯完毕
- Understood. - Good luck, Captain. Dougherty out.
传感器显示没有飞船从星球表面飞过来
Sensors are not picking up any ships coming from the surface.
发出宽幅变量讯号 应该能引起他的注意
Transmit a wideband covariant signal. That ought to get his attention.
他肯定是利用星环掩护行踪
He must be using the planet's rings to mask his approach.
星环发出的重曲辐射正处于最强状态
The metaphasic radiation from the rings is in a state of extreme flux.
我们得避开
We'll steer clear of those.
出来 不管你在哪 快出来
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
长官？
Sir?
这是小时候我妈妈…
That's something that my mother…
坐稳了
Hold on.
打开所有通讯频道
Open all hailing frequencies.
数据 我是皮卡特船长
Data, this is Captain Picard.
数据 请答话
Data, please respond.
如果发射超光速粒子
If we fire tachyon bursts,
他就得调整护盾的调波
it might force him to reset his shield harmonics.
- 趁着他调校 把他给传送过来 - 就这么做
- When he does, we can beam him out. - Make it so.
直接命中 他正在调整护盾
Direct hit. He's resetting his shield harmonics.
把他传送过来
Beam him out.
- 他启动了反传送装置 - 准备进入大气层
- He has activated a transport inhibitor. - Prepare to enter the atmosphere.
我们利用电离层边界来摆脱他
We'll use the ionospheric boundary to shake him.
扫描仪失灵了
Scanners are off-line.
进入逃逸状态 方向140-31
Evasive maneuvers, heading 1-4-0 mark 3-1.
他能驾驶飞船 他还知道怎么运用战略
He can fly a ship. He can anticipate tactical strategies.
很明显 他的大脑仍在运行
Clearly his brain is functioning.
既然他这么能应对危险 我想看看他怎么应对…
We've seen how he responds to threats. I wonder how he would respond…
胡夫 你知道吉尔伯特和沙利文吗？
Mr. Worf, do you know Gilbert and Sullivan?
不 长官 我回来以后
No, sir, I have not had a chance to meet all the new crew members.
还没有来得及认识所有的新船员
since I have been back.
他们是作曲拍档 是十九世纪的
They're composers, Worf, from the 19th century.
数据在出发之前一直在练习他们的作品
Data was rehearsing a production of H.M.S. Pinafore just before he left.
英国水手豪情万丈
A British tar is a soaring soul.
海阔天空 自由奔放
As free as a mountain bird.
磨拳擦掌
His energetic fist should be ready to resist.
对抗强权
A dictatorial word.
一起唱 胡夫
Sing, Worf, sing.
他的鼻孔扩张
His nose should pant.
他的嘴角上翘
And his lip should curl.
他的面颊透焰
His cheeks should flame.
他的眉宇轩昂
And his brow should furl.
他的胸膛起伏
His bosom should heave.
他的心意光明
And his heart should glow.
虎拳一出 敌人立即倒地
And his fist be ever ready for a knockdown blow.
他的鼻孔扩张 嘴角上翘
His nose should pant and his lip should curl.
他的面颊透焰 眉宇轩昂
His cheeks should flame and his brow should furl.
他的胸膛起伏 心意光明
His bosom should heave and his heart should glow.
虎拳一出 敌人立即倒地
And his fist be ever ready for a knockdown blow.
准备好衔接钳
Prepare the docking clamps.
他的眼睛闪出怒火
His eyes should flash with an inborn fire.
眉宇流露藐视神情
His brow with scorn be wrung.
他不为强权而屈服
He never should bow down to a domineering frown.
- 不会为独裁者发言 - 不会为独裁者发言
- Or the tang of a tyrant tongue - Or the tang of a tyrant tongue.
他的心灵破碎
His heart should stamp.
他的怒声不断
And his throat should growl.
他的头发卷曲
His hair should curl.
他的脸孔绷着
And his face should scowl.
他的目光发怒
His eyes should flash.
他的胸膛挺起
And his breast protrude.
这是他一贯的姿势
And this should be his customary attitude.
他在顿脚 把声线压低
His foot should stamp and his throat should growl.
他的头发卷曲他的脸孔…
His hair should curl and his face…
组合惯性超出负荷量
Inertial coupling is exceeding tolerance.
如果再不放开它 两艘船会同归于尽的
If we do not release him, he may destroy both vessels.
我绝不放开
I'm not letting go of him.
我们必须加强减震场
We must stabilize the damping field.
把应急动力传到惯性减震器上
Reroute emergency power to inertial dampers.
自动程序中弹失灵了
The auto- sequencer was damaged by phaser fire.
进入手动操控状态
Transferring controls to manual.
自动程序重新调整 启动减震器
Power sequence realigned. Engaging stabilizers.
- 减震器已经启动了 - 最大动力
- Damping field established. - Maximum power.
行动 胡夫
Now, Mr. Worf.
船长 数据中校被安全抓获
Captain, Commander Data is safely in custody.
船长 我叫加利天 桑那的指挥官
Captain, Subahdar Gallatin, Son'a Command.
我是上将的武官柯蒂斯上尉
Tell him we've received a communiqué from Admiral Dougherty. It's about Data.Lieutenant Curtis,
attaché to Admiral Dougherty.
- 你们没事吧？- 他们对我们很友善
- Are you all right? - We've been treated extremely well.
他们的智力非常发达 洞察力很强
They have incredible mental discipline, clarity of perception.
- 我叫苏捷 - 吉恩·卢克·皮卡特
- My name is Sojef. - Jean-Luc Picard.
我的船员 赫医生 蔡顾问
These are my officers, Dr. Crusher, Counselor Troi.
- 你们要吃点什么吗？- 不 我们是来营救他们的
- Would you like something to eat? - No, we're here to rescue them.
随你们 不过我希望你们能够解除武装
As you wish, but I would ask you to disarm yourselves.
我们这不希望见到武力
This village is a sanctuary of life.
准备把人质传送到飞船上
Prepare the hostages for transport to the ship.
在跟船员接触之前 得先把他们隔离
They should be quarantined before joining the ship's population.
我们收到消息说 他们是被挟持在这的
We were under the impression they were being held against their will.
我们根本不希望有外人来打扰
It's not our custom to have guests here at all,
更不要说挟持他们了
let alone hold anyone against their will.
是一名机器人不让他们离开的
The artificial life- form would not allow them to leave.
事实上 他说这些人使我们的敌人 而且还有更多的敌人要来
In fact, he told us they were our enemies and that more would follow.
- 你们是敌人吗？- 安妮
- Are you our enemy? - Anij.
我们的政策就是不干涉其他文明
My people have a strict policy of non- interference in other cultures.
这是我们的首要指令
It's our Prime Directive.
很显然你们的指令不包括偷窥其他文明吧
Your directive apparently doesn't include spying on other cultures.
很抱歉那个机器人是我的船员
The artificial life- form is a member of my crew.
很显然 他出了故障
Apparently, he was taken ill.
他的正电子矩阵出现了相位差误
There was a phase variance in his positronic matrix.
我们没办法修理
which we were unable to repair.
看来这位船长不大相信
I think the Captain finds it hard to believe.
我们会有修理正电子仪器的技术
that we'd have any skills repairing a positronic device.
我们的技术水平不太明显
Our technological abilities are not apparent.
是因为我们在日常生活中避免使用它们尽量避免使用科技
because we have chosen not to employ them in our daily lives.
我们相信 如果以机械取代人力的话
We believe that when you create a machine to do the work of a man,
等于剥夺了部分人性
you take something away from the man.
我们以前像你们一样探索过太空
But at one time, we explored the galaxy, just as you do.
- 你们拥有曲翘技术？- 技术当然是有的
- You have warp capability? - Capability, yes.
可曲翘推进只会带我们远离这里
But where can warp drive take us except away from here?
我对我们的闯入万分抱歉
I apologize for our intrusion.
因为他们拥有曲翘技术
And because they have warp capability,
所以我们所造成的影响并不是很大
the consequences to their society will be minimal.
你做得很好 吉恩·卢克
You've done a terrific job, Jean-Luc.
赶快收拾行李 离开这鬼地方吧
Now pack your bags and get the hell out of there.
数据怎么样？
How's Data?
被关闭了 拉吉夫正在给他检查
In stasis. La Forge is completing the diagnostic.
你把文件准备好 我们你回来的路上
I'll need all your paperwork tomorrow. We're heading back your way.
设定路线跟我们会合
Set a course to rendezvous with us,
在离开的时候给我们把将船员和装备传送过来
so you can transfer the crew and equipment on your way out.
你们还没结束？
You're not finished here?
还有些工作要收尾 通讯完毕
Just a few loose ends to tie up. Dougherty out.
进来
Come in.
- 你好 - 有空吗？
- Hi. - You got a minute?
当然了
Sure.
我想进行咨询
I need a little counseling.
什么都有第一次
Well, there's a first time for everything.
我是躺下还是怎么着？
So, do I lie down or what?
随你 怎么舒服就怎么来吧
Well, whatever makes you comfortable,
不过这可不是正常的医疗姿势
but this isn't one of the usual therapeutic postures.
- 但这样得舒服 - 你干嘛不坐起来试试？
- But it is comfortable. - Why don't you try sitting up?
你干嘛不躺下试试？
Why don't you try lying down?
看来你今天心情很好啊
Well, you're in quite a mood today.
你到底是来咨询的还是来玩的？
Do you really need counseling or did you come down here to play?
- 我想我出现了中年危机 - 我相信
- I think I'm having a midlife crisis. - I believe you.
我睡不好
I'm not sleeping well.
赫医生有办法治好你的病
Dr. Crusher has something that can take care of that.
赫医生治不了我的心病
What I need, I can't get from Dr. Crusher.
顾问 你觉得我们两个人有没有可能弥补
Counselor, do you think it's possible for two people to go back in time,
以前犯下的错误？
fix a mistake they've made?
在企业号上 什么都有可能
On this ship, anything's possible.
- 好扎！- 好扎？
- Yuck! - Yuck?
- 我从没吻过有胡子的你 - 我吻你 你却说「好刺」？
- I never kissed you with a beard before. - I kiss you and you say "yuck"?
我重建了数据的神经网 取出了这些
I had to reconstruct Data's neural net and replace these.
上面存储了记忆
They contain memory engrams.
- 怎么损坏的？- 桑那人的枪打的
- How were they damaged? - By a Son'a weapon.
毫无疑问 这才是数据出现故障的原因
There's no doubt about it, Captain. That's what caused Data to malfunction.
可是桑那人说是数据发生故障之后
But the Son'a report claims that they didn't fire.
他们才的开枪
until after he malfunctioned.
我可不认为情况是这样
Well, I don't believe it happened that way.
他们干嘛无故冲他开枪？
Why would they fire on him without provocation?
我只知道他在中枪之前是很正常的
All I know is that he was functioning normally until he was shot.
中枪后 故障保护程序就启动了
Then his fail- safe system was activated.
故障保护？
Fail-safe?
他的道德程序接管了所有基本功能
His ethical and moral subroutines took over all of his basic functions.
你是说他仍然
But you're saying that he still knew the difference.
能够分辨是非
between right and wrong.
他只能够分辨是非
In a sense, that's all he knew.
这程序是用来防止
The system is designed to protect Data.
有人趁数据失忆的时候来利用他
against anyone who might try to take advantage of his memory loss.
可他袭击我们 还告诉巴库人我们是威胁
And yet he attacked us, and he told the Ba'ku that we were a threat.
- 假眼不舒服？- 没什么 可能是太累了
- Are the implants bothering you? - I'm all right. I think I'm just tired.
- 佐迪？船长？- 你在企业号上 数据
- Geordi? Captain? - You're on the Enterprise, Data.
我感觉自己好像少了几个记忆棒应该是…
I seem to be missing several memory engrams…
哦 在那儿
There they are.
数据 你最后的印象是什么？
Data, what's the last thing that you remember?
他的鼻孔扩张 嘴角上翘
His nose should pant and his lips should curl.
跟任务有关的
From the mission.
我当时穿着隐形装
I was in an isolation suit.
搜集巴库星的生理功能资料
gathering physiometric data on the Ba'ku.
最后的记忆是我跟着孩子们 爬到了山上
My last memory is going into the hills following some children.
阿添 你还记得那天哪个机器人出现的时候
Artim, do you remember where you were on the day of lightning.
你们在哪吗？
when the artificial life- form appeared to us?
- 水坝旁边的山上 - 能带我们去吗？
- In the hills by the dam. - Can you show us?
你用不着那么怕我
There is no reason to fear me.
我现在处于正常的运行状态
I am now operating within normal parameters.
- 什么？- 因为我被修好了
- What? - They fixed me.
- 船长 那孩子好像很怕我 - 不是针对你 数据
- Captain, the boy is afraid of me. - It's nothing personal, Data.
你得记住 这里的人排斥科技
You have to remember, these people have rejected technology.
而我正好代表着他所排斥的一切
I am the personification of everything they have rejected.
这孩子以前连机器可能都没见过
Until this week, that young man probably never saw a machine,
何况会走路会说话的机器人
let alone one that walks and talks.
舰桥呼叫大副
Bridge to Riker.
能等会儿吗 胡夫？
Can I get back to you, Mr. Worf?
多尔蒂上将在线上 长官
Admiral Dougherty is on the comm link, sir.
接进来吧 你好 上将
Patch him through. Yes, Admiral?
你们怎么还没有离开？
Why haven't you left orbit?
皮卡特船长还在星球上
Captain Picard is still on the surface, sir.
干什么？
Doing what?
他要先弄明白
He didn't want to leave until we could adequately explain.
数据的故障的原因再走
why Data malfunctioned.
他要知道想知道数据还可不可靠
His future in Starfleet could depend on it.
提醒船长 十二小时已经到期了
Remind the Captain his 12 hours are up.
- 是 长官 - 通讯完毕
- Yes, sir. - Dougherty out.
你的身体产生了太多的毒素
Your body is producing far too many toxins.
我们已经达到了基因处理的极限
We've reached the limit of genetic manipulation.
只要联邦朋友们别在节外生枝
I won't need anymore genetic manipulation.
以后我就再也不用做基因处理了
if our Federation friends will allow us to complete this mission.
山上有大量的凯波石岩层
Tricorder functions are limited.
所以三相器没法正常工作
due to heavy deposits of kelbonite in these hills.
用辐射扫描试试？
How about a passive radiation scan?
奇怪
Curious.
湖上好像发射出高密度的微中子
There appear to be strong neutrino emissions coming from the lake.
- 他可以在水里呼吸？- 数据不用呼吸
- Can he breathe underwater? - Data doesn't breathe.
- 不会生锈吗？- 不
- Won't he rust? - No.
船长！船长！
Captain! Captain!
我想我知道是什么在发射微中子了
I believe I know what is causing the neutrino emissions.
这艘分明是联邦的太空船
The vessel is clearly Federation in origin, Captain.
「还有一些工作要收尾」
"Just a few loose ends to tie up."
- 我们对这些事情不感兴趣 - 我有
- We're not interested in such things. - I am.
- 我觉得你最好… - 我要跟着去
- I think it would be wiser if you didn't… - I'm going with you.
这是一项全息工程
It is a holographic projection.
不过还没有完工
Incomplete, I might add.
现在你所看到的是
What you're seeing is a computer-driven image.
由光子和力场形成的电脑图像
created by photons and force fields.
我知道什么是全息图 船长
I know what a hologram is, Captain.
可为什么有人要制作我们村子的全息图呢？
The question is, why would anyone want to create one of our village?
数据 可能是你跟着孩子们 无意中发现了这艘船…
Data, if you were following the children and discovered this ship…
他们朝我开枪是不是为了掩盖这个秘密呢
It is conceivable, I was shot to protect the secret of its existence.
除了想欺骗巴库人外还能有什么原因？
Why would they duplicate this village except to deceive the Ba'ku?
- 想欺骗我们？- 把你们迁离这星球
- Deceive us? - To move you off this planet.
趁着你们晚上熟睡的时候
You go to sleep one night in the village,
把你们集体传送到这艘飞船上
wake up the next morning on this flying holodeck, transported en masse.
过了几天之后
Within a few days,
你们就被不知不觉的安置到另一个类似的星球上
they're relocated on a similar planet without ever realizing it.
为什么联邦或是桑那人要迁走他们呢？
Why would the Federation or the Son'a wish to move the Ba'ku?
我不知道
I don't know.
电脑 结束程序 关闭全息图
Computer, end program. Decloak the vessel.
救命啊！我不会游泳！
Help! I can't swim!
别慌
Don't panic.
有人向我开枪
I've been shot at,
然后把我推下水 又差点被绑架
thrown into the lake out of a ship that's come to abduct us.
我有什么好慌的？
What's there to panic about?
再出现落水的情况时
In the event of a water landing,
我可以被用作浮水装置
I have been designed to serve as a floatation device.
胡夫 人质在汇报情况时
Mr. Worf, did the hostages mention anything about a cloaked ship.
有没有提到一艘隐形船只？
during their debriefing?
- 没有 - 再问问他们
- No, sir. - Debrief them again.
- 你跟人打架了 胡夫？- 没有 长官 这是个高奇
- Have you been in a fight, Mr. Worf? - No, sir. It is a gorch.
高奇？
A gorch?
是青春痘 船长
A pimple, sir.
哦 实际上 一点儿都不显眼
Well, it's hardly noticeable.
光滑得像机器人的屁股 是不是 数据？
Smooth as an android's bottom, eh, Data?
您说什么 长官？
I beg your pardon, sir?
多尔蒂上将问我们为什么还没走
Admiral Dougherty wants to know why we haven't left yet.
我们哪也不去
We're not going anywhere.
到5层
Deck 5.
你们克林冈人什么都长得大 不是吗？
You Klingons never do anything small, do you?
赫医生叫你回来后跟她联系
Dr. Crusher asked to speak to you when you returned.
- 赫医生 - 船长
- Picard to Crusher. - Captain.
那些桑那人拒绝接受检查
The Son'a hostages declined to be examined.
我把他们暂时监管了
I had them confined to quarters.
- 我们的人呢？- 他们很好
- And our people? - They're fine.
他们比很好还好
In fact, they're better than fine.
新陈代谢加快 肌肉结实 精力很充沛
Increased metabolism, improved muscle tone, high energy.
真令人羡慕
We should all be so lucky.
谢谢 医生 完毕
Very well, Doctor. Picard out.
胡夫 等我和罗阿佛谈完话 再释放那些军官
Worf, don't release the Son'a officers till I've talked to Ahdar Ru'afo.
是 长官
Aye, sir.
大副 可不可以…
Commander, may I…
电脑 给我来点音乐
Computer, music.
- 不 不要这种 要拉丁音乐 - 请指定
- No. Not that, something Latin. - Specify.
曼波舞曲
The mambo.
这才像样
That's more like it.
你多大了？
How old are you?
我们在 快要自我毁灭的时候离开了家园
We came here from a solar system on the verge of self- annihilation,
当时我们的武器足以摧毁星球上所有生命
where technology had created weapons that threatened to destroy all life.
一小群人出发去寻找新的家园
A small group of us set off to find a new home,
一个远离其他世界威胁的家园
a home that would be isolated from the threats of other worlds.
那是309年以前的事情了
That was 309 years ago.
之后你们就不再衰老
And you haven't aged a day since then.
事实上我们刚来的时候
Actually, I was a good deal older when we arrived,
比现在衰老得多
in terms of my physical condition.
巴库星的星环
There's an unusual metaphasic radiation.
发出一种不同寻常的重曲辐射
coming from the planet's rings.
它能够持续再生我们的基因结构
It continuously regenerates our genetic structure.
- 你应该有所体会了吧 - 刚开始体会
- You must've noticed the effects by now. - We've just begun to.
- 我猜你有七十五岁了 - 不 我十二岁
- I suppose you're 75. - No, I'm 12.
这要等到他成年以后
The metaphasic radiation won't begin to affect him.
重曲辐射才会对他起作用
until he reaches maturity.
对大多数人来说 你们拥有的财富
To most off- landers, what you have here is more valuable than.
比黄金更有价值
gold- pressed latinum.
恐怕这正是有人
I'm afraid that's the reason that someone.
想要夺走你们家园的原因
may be trying to take your world away from you.
那个机器人说得对
The artificial life-form was right.
如果不是因为数据 我想你们现在可能已经被人迁走了
If it were not for Data, it's probable that you would be relocated by now.
我们怎么去保护自己？
How can we possibly defend ourselves?
一旦拿起武器 那就跟他们一样了
The moment we pick up a weapon, we become one of them.
- 我们就失去了我们本质 - 也许用不着这样
- We lose everything we are. - It may not come to that.
很明显阴谋的主使者不希望有人知道这件事
Clearly, the architects of this conspiracy want to keep it a secret,
不仅要瞒你们 还得瞒我们那边的人
not only from you, but from my people, as well.
我不会让他们得逞
I don't intend to let them.
我们一直都知道要想生存 就得与世隔绝
We've always known that to survive, we had to remain apart.
可是这并不容易
It hasn't been easy.
很多年轻人对外面的世界充满了好奇
Many of the young people want to know more about the offland.
他们向往那种快速的生活节奏
They're attracted to stories of a faster pace of life.
我们这些过惯快节奏生活的人
Most of my people who live that fast a life.
愿意不惜一切让节奏慢下来
would sell their souls to slow it down.
可你不是？
But not you?
偶尔也会
There are days.
你跟外面世界的其他人不太一样 皮卡特
You don't live up to your reputation as an offlander, Picard.
哦 我得为外面世界说一句 有很多像我这样的人
Well, in defense of offlanders, there are many more people like me.
有机会青春永驻却不心动的
Who wouldn't be tempted by the promise of perpetual youth?
我不这么想
I don't think so.
那是因为你太看得起我了
You give me more credit than I deserve.
我当然动心 谁不动心？
Well, of course I'm tempted. Who wouldn't be?
可是在我那个世界的历史中 有着最黑暗的几个篇章
But some of the darkest chapters in the history of my world.
某些大集团为了满足私欲
involve the forced relocation of a small group of people.
而驱逐牺牲一小群人
to satisfy the demands of a large one.
我希望我们能从中的到教训
I'd hoped that we had learned from our mistakes but.
看来还是有人没有
it seems that some of us haven't.
真是手艺精湛呐
This is extraordinary craftsmanship.
这些都是学生们做的
It's the work of students.
他们很快就要成为学徒了
They're almost ready to become apprentices.
三四十年之后
In 30 or 40 years,
其中一部分会成为艺术家
some of them will take their place among the artisans.
当学徒要当三十年
Apprenticing for 30 years.
你们就用这办法寻求自律？
Did your people's mental discipline develop here?
问题太多了 真不愧是探索者
More questions. Always the explorer.
- 如果你待的够久就会改变的 - 是吗？
- If you stay long enough, that'll change. - Will it?
你不会再去思考昨天
You stop reviewing what happened yesterday,
也不会再去计划明天
stop planning for tomorrow.
我想问你一个问题
Let me ask you a question.
你有没有体验过永恒的刹那？
Have you ever experienced a perfect moment in time?
永恒的刹那？
A perfect moment?
时间好象停住了
When time seemed to stop.
也好像永远都活在那一刻
and you could almost live in that moment?
我第一次从太空看见地球的时候
Seeing my home planet from space for the first time.
对 没错
Yes, exactly.
没什么比感知这东西更复杂了
Nothing more complicated than perception.
你们探索宇宙
You explore the universe.
可是我们却发现生命中某一时刻
We've discovered that a single moment in time.
本身就可以成为宇宙
can be a universe in itself,
其中有无限的活力
full of powerful forces.
很多人甚至都意识不到现在的存在
Most people aren't aware enough of the now to even notice.
真希望抽出几百年去学习
I wish I could spare a few centuries to learn.
我们学习了一百年之后才知道用不着这么久
It took us centuries to learn that it doesn't have to take centuries to learn.
有一件事 我想不明白
There's one thing I don't understand.
三百年了 你没学过游泳？
In 300 years, you never learned to swim?
我只是还没有时间
I just haven't got around to it yet.
不知道你是否意识到自己的可靠感 吉恩·卢克·皮卡特
I wonder if you're aware of the trust you engender, Jean-Luc Picard.
- 根据我的经验 这不大像… - 外来人？
- In my experience, it's unusual for… - For an offlander?
这样年轻的人
For someone so young.
- 佐迪？- 船长
- Geordi? - Captain.
看来不是我的假眼出了问题
As it turns out, there wasn't anything wrong with my implants at all.
而是我的眼睛开始好转了
There was something right with my eyes.
在赫医生把我的假眼取走之后
When Dr. Crusher removed the ocular connection,
她发现我的视觉神经…
she found that the cells around my optic nerve had…
开始再生了
Started to regenerate.
可能不会持久 就算不会…
It may not last, and if it doesn't, I just…
我想 我想在我离开之前…
I just wanted, before we go…
你知道我从来没看过日出
You know, I've never seen a sunrise,
至少看到的不是你们所看到的那种日出
at least, not the way you see them.
请进
Come.
我不明白你为什么不放了我的人 船长？
Am I to understand that you're not releasing my men, Captain?
我们发现了全息船
We found the holoship.
罗阿佛 能不能让我和船长…
Ru'afo, why don't you let the Captain and me…
不！
No!
这个任务就因为联邦而一再出错
This entire mission has been one Federation blunder after another.
赶快放了我的人
You will return my men.
不然我会终止合作摧毁你的船
or this alliance will end with the destruction of your ship.
你看上去很不错 很精神 吉恩·卢克
You're looking well, Jean-Luc. Rested.
我不会让你迁走巴库人 我会向联邦议会报告此事
I won't let you move them, Admiral. I will take this to the Federation Council.
我就是按照议会的指示在办事
I'm acting on orders from the Federation Council.
议会批准你执行违背首要指令的任务？
How can there be an order to abandon the Prime Directive?
首要指令并不适用
The Prime Directive doesn't apply.
这些人并不是巴库星的本地人
These people are not indigenous to this planet.
本来就不该长生不老
They were never meant to be immortal.
我们只是让他们回复正常的自然进化
We'll simply be restoring them to their natural evolution.
我们凭什么
Who the hell are we.
来决定这些人的下一步进化程序？
to determine the next course of evolution for this people?
吉恩·卢克 那只有六百个人
Jean-Luc, there are 600 people down there.
我们可以利用这种辐射的再生性
We'll be able to use the regenerative properties.
造福上亿人
of this radiation to help billions.
桑那人发明了一种技术
The Son'a have developed a procedure.
可以从星球的星环中提取重曲粒子
to collect the metaphasic particles from the planet's rings.
- 位于联邦范围的星球 - 没错
- A planet in Federation space. - That's right.
我们有星球他们有技术
We have the planet. They have the technology,
我们没法复制的技术 你知道这代表什么？
a technology we can't duplicate. You know what that makes us?
合作伙伴
Partners.
这种伙伴不亚于低级强盗
Our partners are nothing more than petty thugs.
在地球上 石油曾经让低级强盗成为世界领袖
On Earth, petroleum once turned petty thugs into world leaders.
曲翘技术使
Warp drive transformed.
罗武伦人成立了帝国
a bunch of Romulan thugs into an empire.
我们能应付桑那人 对此我不担心
We can handle the Son'a. I'm not worried about that.
100年前也有人说过罗武伦人算不了什么
Someone probably said the same thing about the Romulans a century ago.
重曲粒子可以延长寿命
With metaphasics, lifespans will be doubled.
一种全新的医学将会出现
An entire new medical science will evolve.
我知道你的首席工程师的
I understand your chief engineer has the use of his eyes.
视觉已经开始恢复
for the first time in his life.
你忍心让他得而复失？
Will you take that away from him?
整个荆棘区都是重曲粒子
There are metaphasic particles all over the Briar Patch.
为什么非要选中这个星球？
Why does it have to be this one planet?
只有星环里的高密度粒子才有用
It's the concentration in the rings that makes the whole damn thing work.
别问我 别让我解释
Don't ask me to explain it.
我只知他们把什么东西注入星环
I only know they inject something into the rings.
进行热解反应
that starts a thermolytic reaction.
之后星球上将有好几代不能住人
When it's over, the planet will be uninhabitable for generations.
将军 推迟程序 让我们的人研究一下这种技术
Admiral, delay the procedure. Let my people look at the technology.
我们最优秀的科学家已研究过了 我们找不到其他办法
Our best scientific minds already have. We can't find any other way to do this.
那就让桑那人现在巴库星上建一个殖民地
Then the Son'a can establish a separate colony.
然后我们从长计议
on the planet until we do.
那要等十年时候
It would take 10 years of normal exposure.
他们的状况才会开始改进
to begin to reverse their condition.
他们有人活不了那么久
Some of them won't survive that long.
还有 他们不愿意住在荆棘区
Besides, they don't want to live in the middle of the Briar Patch.
- 谁愿意？- 巴库人
- Who would? - The Ba'ku.
可是这违背了联邦成立时的基本原则
We are betraying the principles upon which the Federation was founded.
使它玷污联邦的精神
It's an attack upon its very soul.
这会毁掉巴库文明
And it will destroy the Ba'ku,
就像我们历史上
just as cultures have been destroyed.
每一次强制迁移所摧毁的文明一样
in every other forced relocation throughout history.
吉恩·卢克 我们只不过是迁走六百个人
Jean-Luc, we're only moving 600 people.
要祸害多少人 将军 才算是犯错？
How many people does it take, Admiral, before it becomes wrong?
一千？五万？一百万？
A thousand? Fifty thousand? A million?
要多少人才行 将军？
How many people does it take, Admiral?
我命令你前往哥伦星系
I'm ordering you to the Goren system.
我还命令你释放桑那军官
I'm also ordering the release of the Son'a officers.
你想怎么投诉就怎么投诉 船长
File whatever protests you wish to, Captain.
不过等你投诉时 我们已经完工了
By the time you do, this will all be done.
加利天
Gallatin.
看来 那个顽固的星舰船长终于放了你
So, the righteous Starfleet captain finally released you.
对
Yes.
你们在星球上遇到什么困难了吗？
Did you encounter any problems on the surface?
没有 长官
No, sir.
不过跟他们相处真不好受
But it wasn't easy being among them.
没错 别忘了他们对我们做过什么
I'm sure. Just don't forget what they did to us.
我们很快就能把他们搞定
We'll have them rounded up in a day or two.
我们再也用不着联邦的全息船了
We needn't bother with a Federation holoship anymore.
- 把关押舱准备好 - 是长官
- Just get the holding cells ready. - Yes, sir.
我会想念这拉皮技术的
I'm going to miss these little flesh-stretching sessions of ours,
亲爱的
my dear.
改变传送器的线路 这招很聪明 长官
Re- routing the transport grid to avoid detection was wise, sir.
可是两点钟之后就很少有人使用传送器了
However, the transporter is rarely used after 0200 hours.
准备坐船长游艇出去兜风？
Taking the Captain's yacht out for a spin?
七公吨极元炸药
Seven metric tons of ultritium explosives,
八挺脉冲枪
eight tetryon pulse launchers.
十支同位磁解枪
and 10 isomagnetic disintegrators.
你好像是要去去打猎
Looks like you're planning on doing some hunting.
全都回自己的岗位去
Return to your quarters.
- 这是命令 - 你没穿制服 没权下令
- That's an order. - No uniform, no orders.
船长 知道他们的处境后
Captain, how could I look at another sunrise.
我怎么还能心安理得的看日出呢？
knowing what my sight cost these people?
我现在有必要指出 这种环境异常
I feel obliged to point out that the environmental anomalies.
可能会导致莫中年轻人所特有的反叛性
may have stimulated certain rebellious instincts common to youth,
这会影响所有人的判断力
which could affect everyone's judgment.
当然 我是例外
Except mine, of course.
那好 数据 你说说我们应该怎么做？
Okay, Data, what do you think we should do?
鸣金击鼓 准备战斗
Saddle up. Lock and load.
只要星球上还住着人 他们就不会动手
They won't begin the procedure while the planet is still inhabited,
我们的任务就是要尽量把人留在星球上
so our job is to keep the planet inhabited.
韦 佐迪 你们把飞船开除荆棘区
Will, Geordi, go back and put a face on what's happening here.
把巴库人的情况报告给议会
Make the Council see the Ba'ku.
人们对自己不知道的人所遭受的
It's too easy to turn a blind eye.
痛苦总是容易视而不见
to the suffering of a people you don't know.
- 我会快去快回的 - 我们会尽量撑久一点
- I'll be back before you know it. - We'll hold out as long as we can.
在模拟操作时 注入器表现极佳
The injector performs perfectly in every simulation.
长官 企业号已经离开
Sir, as the Enterprise left orbit,
但有一艘小艇降落到星球上
one of their support craft went down to the surface.
什么？
What?
看上去是船长游艇 艇上有五个人
Appeared to be the Captain's yacht. Five persons onboard.
我们不能再等到早上
We're not waiting until morning.
今晚就把那些人全都传送上来
Take the shuttles and get everyone off the surface tonight.
加利天
Gallatin.
如果皮卡特和他的人插手 就干掉他们
If Picard or any of his people interfere, eliminate them.
我们要暂时离开村子 只带上必需品
We're leaving the village! Take only what you need!
带上粮食 可能得过几天我们才能回来
Bring food! We may not be back for days!
这是反传送器
It is a transport inhibitor.
有了它太空船就没法把人从地面上传送走
It will help prevent spaceships from beaming anyone off the surface.
山脉上这些凯波岩
These veins of kelbonite running through the hills.
可以干扰到他们的传送器
will interfere with their transporters,
等到了没有凯波岩的山路上时
and when the terrain forces us away from the deposits,
我们就会用反传送器来阻止他们
then we'll use transport inhibitors as a compensation.
山里面有很密集的凯波岩
The mountains have the heaviest concentration of kelbonite.
到了那儿 传送器就会完全失效
Once there, it'll make transport virtually impossible.
山里面有个山洞
There are caves in those mountains.
对 到了那儿我们就可以撑上好几天
Then we should be able to hold out for a long time once we're there,
不过他们不会轻易让我们到那儿的
but they're not gonna make it easy for us to get there.
船长！
Captain!
我们已经启动了村子周围的反传送器
We've activated the transport inhibitors around the village.
很好
Good.
赶快带大家离开！
Let's move these people out!
传送器全部失灵了
Transporters are not functioning.
他们用反传送器挡住了电波
They're blocking the beams with some kind of inhibitors.
我们得先找到并摧毁它们
We'll have to locate and destroy them.
不 不 儿子 你拿的东西太多了 我们得爬好长的山路呢
No, no. Son, you're carrying too much. We have a long climb ahead of us.
我们损失了三架反传送器 有段路出现了空隙
We've lost three transport inhibitors. There's a gap in the field.
阿添！
Artim!
爸爸！
Father!
他们沿着矿脉行走
They're following the kelbonite deposits,
利用干扰物来对抗传送器
using the interference to block our transporters.
- 有什么建议？- 让我下去 我要去跟皮卡特谈谈
- Recommendations? - Take me down. Let me talk to Picard.
谈谈！
Talk!
我们应该派人下去把他们强制带走
We should send down an assault team and take them by force.
这种做法不能接受
That is not an acceptable option.
如果有人受伤 那么联邦所给予的支持…
If people get hurt, all the support we have in the Federation…
联邦的支持
Federation support,
联邦的程序 联邦的规定
Federation procedures, Federation rules.
看看镜子 上将 联邦已经老了
Look in the mirror, Admiral. The Federation is old.
在过去的两年里
In the past 24 months,
联邦受到各大力量的挑战
they've been challenged by every major power in the quadrant.
博格 卡塔锡安还有自治领
The Borg, the Cardassians, the Dominion,
都闻到了联邦衰败的气息
they all smell the scent of death on the Federation.
所以你们才跟我们合作
That's why you've embraced our offer,
因为这会让联邦拥有新生命
because it will give your dear Federation new life.
你是多么渴望新生命啊 将军？
Well, how badly do you want it, Admiral?
因为你现在必须做出艰难的选择
Because there are hard choices to be made now.
如果让企业号联络上议会
If the Enterprise gets through with news.
知道他们那勇敢的船长
about their brave Captain's valiant struggle.
见义勇为的扶助弱小的巴库人 那联邦政治家可能就会动摇
on behalf of the defenseless Ba'ku, your Federation politicians will waver.
你们的联邦民意调查将会激起民愤
Your Federation opinion polls will open a public debate.
你的联邦盟友也要讨个说法 还要我说下去吗？
Your Federation allies will want their say. Need I go on?
除了全面进攻 还有个办法
There's an alternative to an all- out assault.
出动辅运蜂 把他们一个个传送上来
Isolinear tags would allow our transporters to lock onto them.
那得一个一个锁定 太浪费时间
We'd have to tag every one of them.
我们耗不起
That would take time, and we don't have it.
再过19个小时
The Enterprise is only 19 hours.
企业号就能联邦取得联系
from communications range with the Federation.
- 我会命令瑞克调头回来 - 你是说皮卡特的大副
- I'll order Riker to turn around. - Picard's first officer.
你以为他会听你的？
You really believe he'll listen?
我的飞船可以在企业号
My ships are capable of intercepting the Enterprise.
飞离荆棘区之前拦住它
before it reaches the perimeter.
我可以派船去…
I could send them to…
去押送它回来
To escort it back.
但瑞克中校未必肯回来
But Commander Riker might not want to come.
派出你的飞船吧
Send your ships.
- 你喜欢做机器人吗？- 我努力想要超越自己
- Do you like being a machine? - I aspire to be more than I am.
我知道原因 这样我们就不会再害怕你了
I know why. So people like us won't be afraid of you anymore.
也许吧
Perhaps.
你从来都不累吗？
Don't you ever get tired?
不累 我的电池自动的持续充电
My power cells continually recharge themselves.
我想象不出做机器人是什么感觉
I can't imagine what it's like to be a machine.
说出来你可能会惊讶
Perhaps it would surprise you to know.
我也经常想象着做孩子是什么样的感觉
that I have often tried to imagine what it is like to be a child.
- 真的吗？- 是的
- Really? - Really.
第一条就是孩子们的腿会比较短
For one thing, your legs are shorter than everyone else's.
但是他们会不停的生长
But they are in a constant state of growth.
- 你有没有觉得难以适应呢？- 适应？
- Do you find it difficult to adapt? - Adapt?
孩子们的骨骼
A child's specifications are never the same.
每一秒钟都在发生变化
from one moment to the next.
可奇怪的是 你不会被自己绊倒
It is a wonder you do not trip over your own feet.
有时侯会的
Sometimes I do.
我的腿长永远是87.2厘米 那是设计好的
My legs are exactly 87.2 centimeters in length.
在我刚出厂的时候它们就是87.2厘米
They were 87.2 centimeters the day I was created.
我想等我报废的那天它们还会是87.2厘米
They will be 87.2 centimeters the day I go off-line.
因为只有规格不变 我才能够正常的运行
My operation depends on specifications that do not change.
我永远都不会知道成长的滋味
I will never know the experience of growing up.
也没有被自己绊倒过
or tripping over my own feet.
但是不会有大人整天对你啰啰嗦嗦
But you've never had adults telling you what to do all the time.
要你早睡 要你吃你不想吃的东西
or bedtimes or having to eat food you don't like.
我倒是很愿意用按时上床睡觉来交换
I would gladly accept the requirement of a bedtime.
来体验一下做孩子的感觉
in exchange for knowing what it is like to be a child.
- 机器人玩耍吗？- 是的 我会拉小提琴
- Do machines ever play? - Yes. I play the violin,
而且我的棋艺也相当不错
and my chess routines are quite advanced.
不 我是说 你有没有开心的玩耍过？
No, I mean, haven't you ever just played for fun?
可是机器人不知道开心这回事
Androids do not have fun.
听着 要想知道做孩子是什么感觉
Look, if you wanna know what it's like to be a child,
就得学会玩耍
you need to learn to play.
船长
Captain.
胡夫先生 你该理发了
Mr. Worf, you need a haircut.
克林冈人在扎塔拉期
Accelerated hair growth is often experienced by Klingons.
头发总是长的很快
during jak'tahla.
- 扎塔拉期？- 翻译过来 就是青春期
- Jak'tahla? - Roughly translated, puberty,
虽然对克林冈人来说并不太准确
although for a Klingon, that scarcely does it justice.
一有情绪波动或是有暴力倾向
Any severe mood swings, unusual aggressive tendencies,
- 马上就通知我 - 是 长官
- you let me know at once. - Yes, sir.
巴库人该休息了 根据地理扫描
The Ba'ku need some rest, sir. According to the geo-scan,
几公里内这里比较安全
this is the safest area within the next few kilometers.
很好 休息一小时
Very well. We'll take an hour.
- 分配一下食物 - 是 长官
- Have them break out some rations. - Aye, sir.
山脊的背面就是山洞
Right beyond that ridge is where the caves begin.
里面可以躲上几天
We can hide there for days.
桑那人肯定已经扫描过这一带的地形
By now, the Son'a will have scanned this area.
他们和我们一样清楚
They'll know that as well as we do.
三百年来我第一次见到秃头的男人
It's been 300 years since I've seen a bald man.
你为什么一直都没结婚？
How is it that you never married?
别告诉我你是因为还没来得及
And don't tell me it's just because you haven't got around to it yet.
- 为什要急呢？- 我得警告你
- What's the rush? - I should warn you,
我可是很吸引成熟女性的
I've always been attracted to older women.
- 你怎么做到的？- 干嘛问那么多
- How are you doing this? - No more questions.
中校 侦测到两艘桑那船只想要拦截我们
Commander, I'm showing two Son'a ships on an intercept course.
- 什么时候追到？- 十八分钟后
- How long till they reach us? - Eighteen minutes.
我们至少一小时后离开荆棘区进行通讯
We won't be able to get a transmission out of here for at least another hour.
他们再呼叫我们
They're hailing us.
告诉他们 我们的通讯系统失灵了
Tell them our transceiver assembly is down,
只能发送 不能接收
that we can send messages but not receive them.
- 我觉得他们不会相信 - 为什么？
- I don't think they believe us. - Why not?
光子鱼雷
Photon torpedo.
通讯失灵就用这么打招呼吗？
Isn't that the universal greeting when communications are down?
一般对不喜欢的人才会这么打招呼
I think it's the universal greeting when you don't like someone.
全速前进
Full impulse.
飞船在荆棘区经不起全速前进 中校
Manifolds can't handle full impulse in the Patch, Commander.
如果我们快不过他们 飞船上所有的人都会死的
If we don't outrun them, the manifolds'll be the only thing left on the ship.
- 我去工程室 - 红色警报！全体人员 准备作战！
- I'll be in Engineering. - Red alert! All hands, battle stations!
你有没有觉得你的胸部变得结实了？
And have you noticed how your boobs have started to firm up?
这年代 大家都不重视这个了
Not that we care about such things in this day and age.
谢谢你 数据
Thank you, Data.
我现在真的很想尝尝动物的鲜血
I've an odd craving for the blood of a live Kolar beast.
肯定又是环境造成的影响
This environment must be affecting me again.
你有没有觉得你的胸部开始变得结实呢？
And have you noticed how your boobs have started to firm up?
因为这个年代 实在是…
Not that we care about…
快隐蔽！
Take cover!
这是辅运蜂 可以跟踪传送
Isolinear tags. The transporters can lock onto them.
我们要找地方躲起来
We have to find shelter.
下一个山脚那有个山洞
There's a cavern at the base of the next hill.
这边走！
This way!
- 护盾功能只剩60%了 - 这是工程室呼叫舰桥
- Shields at 60%. - Engineering to Bridge.
重氢快要着火了
We're burning deuterium down here.
用不着桑那人动手 我们也会自行爆炸
We're gonna blow ourselves up. We won't need any help from the Son'a!
那团星云里面是什么？
What's inside that nebula cluster?
慧星碎块 大团不稳定的易燃气体
Cometary debris, pockets of unstable metreon gas.
我们不能进去 长官
We don't want to go in there, sir.
不 要进去 我来操作 少尉
Yes, we do. I'll take it from here, Ensign.
看来现在我们只能以险取胜了
Time to use the Briar Patch the way Brer Rabbit did.
大家进洞里去 快点儿！所有人！
Inside the caves, quickly! Everyone! This way!
这边儿
Inside.
现在我真的很想打一架 长官
Definitely feeling aggressive tendencies, sir.
他们发射了同位线炸弹 一股空间裂缝正在形成
They've detonated an isolytic burst. A subspace tear is forming.
荧幕显像
On screen.
奇托姆协议不是禁止使用次空间武器吗？
I thought subspace weapons were banned by the Khitomer Accord.
记得提醒我提出抗议
Remind me to lodge a protest.
我们的曲翘核心会吸引裂缝
Our warp core is acting like a magnet to the tear.
就好像沿着太空拉开拉链
We're pulling it like a zipper across space.
有什么办法？
Options?
- 我们可以扔掉核心 - 这会停止裂缝吗？
- We could eject the core. - Will that stop the tear?
你问倒我了中校
You got me, Commander.
这就是你的专业建议？
That's your expert opinion?
引爆曲翘核心可能会停止裂缝
Detonating the warp core might neutralize the cascade.
也可能不会
Then again, it might not.
次空间武器是难以预测的 所以才会被禁用
Subspace weapons are unpredictable. That's why they were banned.
裂缝正在向我们靠近
The tear is closing on us.
- 十五秒以后到达 - 扔出核心
- Impact in 15 seconds. - Eject the core.
我已经扔了
I just did.
十秒后到达
Impact in 10 seconds.
引爆！
Detonate!
叫医务人员过来！
Get me a medic over here!
成功了 中校 裂缝被封住了
It worked, Commander. The tear has been sealed.
对 可他们还会再来一次的
Yeah, but there's nothing to stop them from doing it again,
到时后我们就没有核心了
and we're fresh out of warp cores.
我们距离通讯范围还有36分钟 长官
We're still 36 minutes from transmission range, sir.
看来我们得躲着点这些混蛋了
We're through running from these bastards.
又有43人被抓走了 长官
Another 43 reported taken, sir.
船长 他们想把我们逼出去 然后再用辅运蜂锁定我们
Captain, they're trying to drive us out so their drones can tag us.
根据地下热水口的资料分析
With all the hydrothermal vents in the substrata,
我想这个山洞的结构不会支持的太久
the structural integrity of this cavern is not going to hold for long.
- 有其他出口吗？- 不知道
- Is there another way out of here? - I don't know.
船长 跟着水源 也许能找到出口
Captain, tracking the water's course may reveal another exit.
胡夫 跟我们来
Mr. Worf, come with us.
我探测到这块方解石壁后面有氮氧气流 船长
I'm reading a nitrogen- oxygen flow behind that calcite formation, Captain.
如果炸掉它山洞能不能撑得住？
Will this structure hold if we were to blast through?
我想可以的长官
I believe it is safe, sir.
开火
Fire.
叫大家到这边洞里来
Get everybody into those caves,
大家一进去就设置力场
and set up force fields once they're inside.
是 长官
Aye, sir.
佐迪 那些是易燃气团吗？
Geordi, are those pockets of metreon gas?
对 中校 具有爆炸性 我建议我们保持距离
Yes, Commander. Highly volatile. I'd recommend we keep our distance.
不 我要让储存勺大量收集这些气团
Negative. I want to use the ramscoop to collect as much of it as we can.
什么目的？
The purpose being?
我的目的是
The purpose being,
要把它塞进桑那人的喉咙里
I intend to shove it down the Son'a's throat.
中校 但如果他们的武器击中那些气团的话 那我们…
Commander, if one of their weapons hits that gas…
这是我们唯一的出路 丹尼尔斯
It's our only way out of here, Mr. Daniels.
这以后可能会被人们
I wouldn't be surprised if history remembers this.
称为瑞克战术
as the Riker Maneuver.
如果成功的话
If it works.
电脑 进入人工驾驶模式
Computer, access manual steering column.
进入人工驾驶模式
Transfer helm controls to manual.
舰桥 已到达最大储存容量
Bridge, storage cells are at maximum capacity.
他们正在启动武器部署 长官
They're powering their forward weapons array, sir.
引爆储存勺 准备 全速推进
Blow out the ramscoop. Stand by. Full thrusters.
储存勺发射
Ramscoop released.
船长
Captain.
数据 蔡 快带他们走
Data, Troi, keep these people moving.
带他们走
Bring them out.
我猜辅运蜂过不了多久就会过来
I suspect it won't be long before the drones get here.
快走
Keep moving! Keep moving!
上面有山洞 那儿会安全一点
They found caves on higher ground. We'll be safe there.
船长 快过来看看这个 他的DNA分析
Captain, take a look at this med- scan, his DNA profile.
- 这怎么可能？- 应该问问他们
- How can that be possible? - Maybe we should ask them.
阿添 你在干什么？快走
Artim, what are you doing? Come.
- 这是最后一组吗？- 是的 长官
- Is this the last group? - Yes, sir.
叫他们准备出去 我们得赶快
Get them ready to move out. We need to hurry.
安妮找阿添去了
Anij went to find Artim.
- 跟图奈尔走！- 不 我要跟你在一起！
- Go with Tournel! - No, I wanna stay with you!
那边更安全 快！
It is safer there. Go!
呼叫皮卡特！
Worf to Picard!
两人生命迹象 其中一个生命垂危
Two life- signs, one of them extremely faint.
有将近4吨的石头 拦住了我们的去路
There are almost 4 metric tons of rock blocking our way.
不 那会震塌别的山洞
No. That might cause another cave-in.
安妮？
Anij?
- 胡夫呼叫皮卡特 - 胡夫？我听得到你
- Worf to Picard. - Worf? Yes, I can hear you.
我们设法救你们出来 长官
We are trying to get to you, sir.
安妮
Anij.
救援马上就到
Help is on the way.
- 胡夫 快点 安妮受了伤 - 有多严重 船长？
- Worf, hurry. Anij is hurt. - How bad is she, Captain?
- 她快不行了 - 我们尽快
- I'm losing her. - We're coming as fast as we can.
安妮 别离开我
Anij, stay with me.
给我力量 让我留住你
Help me find the power to keep you in this moment.
别离开我
Stay with me.
不要放弃这一刻
Don't let go of this moment.
情况很稳定
She's stabilizing.
- 搬动她安全吗？- 比留在这安全
- Is it safe to move her? - Safer than leaving her here.
你还以为要几百年才能学会
And you thought it would take centuries to learn.
叫他们投降 我就不把你告上军事法庭
Order them to surrender and I promise you won't be court-martialed.
如果只有上军事法庭才能让联邦知道这件事的话
If a court- martial is the only way to let the people of the Federation know.
那我乐意至极
what is happening here, I welcome it.
企业号摧毁了我一艘战船
The Enterprise has destroyed one of my ships!
另一艘也起火求救
The other is on fire, requesting assistance.
企业号只会自卫还击
The Enterprise would only fire to defend itself.
罗阿佛一定曾下令攻击
Ru'afo must have ordered the attack.
我相信他事先
I can't believe he would have given that order.
肯定征得了你的同意 将军
without your consent, Admiral.
我在想我们俩谁会上军事法庭
I wonder which of us will be facing that court-martial.
这样下去不会再有什么好处了
There's nothing further to be gained from this.
说得对 现在一切就要结束了
You're right. This is going to end now.
巴库人非要留下来 请便
The Ba'ku want to stay on the planet. Let them.
- 我照样发射注入器 - 你不能这么做…
- I'm going to launch the injector. - You're not going to launch anything…
六小时后 这星系的一切生物
In six hours, every living thing in this system.
都会死亡或者重伤
will be dead or dying.
你忍心杀死自己的同胞 罗阿佛？
You would kill your own people, Ru'afo?
自己的父母？兄弟姐妹？
Your own parents, brothers, sisters?
将军 你难道不知道？
Didn't you know, Admiral?
桑那和巴库是同一种族
The Son'a and the Ba'ku are the same race.
皮卡特刚刚告诉了我们
Picard just told us.
我们的DNA是一样的
Our DNA is identical.
你是哪个？加纳？罗佛尔？
Which one were you? Gal'na? Ro'tin?
那些名字 那些孩子已经永远消失了
Those names, those children are gone forever.
他在说什么？
What's he talking about?
在一百年前 有一群年轻人
A century ago, a group of our young people.
他们想要追随外面的生活方式
wanted to follow the ways of the offlanders.
他们想要企图夺权 但终于失败…
They tried to take over the colony, and when they failed…
你把我们驱逐 任由我们自生自灭
When we failed, you exiled us to die slowly.
你是说你是罗佛尔？
You're Ro'tin, aren't you?
从声音我听得出来
There's something in the voice.
你是他的朋友加纳？
Would you be his friend, Gal'na?
你小时候我帮你母亲给你洗过澡
I helped your mother bathe you when you were a child.
她仍然经常会谈起你
She still speaks of you.
你令联邦介入了一场家族仇恨 将军
You've brought the Federation into the middle of a blood feud, Admiral.
孩子们回来驱逐上一代
The children have returned to expel their elders,
只因为他们曾被驱逐
just as they were once expelled,
只不过罗阿佛的报复已经升级为赶尽杀绝
except that Ru'afo's need for revenge has now escalated into parricide.
我这样做都是为了联邦
It was for the Federation.
这一切都是为了联邦
It was all for the Federation.
我们赶快离开这里吧 任务结束了
We're taking this ship out of here. This mission is over.
- 还没有结束 - 我说结束了！
- It is not over. - It is over!
你有什么资格来命令我？
I do not take orders from you!
如果你不顾居民的死活 发射注入器
If you launch the injector while the planet's still populated,
联邦绝不会放过你…
the Federation will pursue you until…
联邦永远也不会知道真相
The Federation will never know what happened here.
多尔蒂将军不过来和我们一起吃晚饭了
Admiral Dougherty will not be joining us for dinner.
启动收集站
Deploy the collector.
- 你对我的命令有意见吗？- 可以单独谈谈吗？
- Do you have a problem with that order? - May I talk to you alone?
- 启动收集站 - 是 长官
- Deploy the collector. - Yes, sir.
迁走他们就行了 何必赶尽杀绝…
Moving them is one thing. Killing them all…
没有人比你更恨他们了 加纳
No one hated them more than you, Gal'na.
我们好不容易才走到了今天
We've come a long way together.
我们计划了这么多年 就是为了这一刻
This is the moment we've planned for so many years.
把星际舰队的人带走 关到舰尾的货舱里
Separate the Starfleet personnel and secure them in the aft cargo hold.
记得把皮卡特也关进去
See that Picard joins them.
进行热解反应时
The shields in that section.
舰尾的货物无法抵抗热辐射
won't protect them against the thermolytic reaction.
谢谢你提醒我
Thank you for reminding me.
吉恩·卢克
Jean-Luc.
你跟我来
Come with me.
你做人质的时候 肯定感觉怪怪的
It must have been strange for you when you were a hostage,
周围全是多年前所熟悉的朋友和家人
surrounded by all the friends and family you knew all those years ago,
每个人都和以前一模一样
each one looking exactly as they did then.
就像 在用孩童的眼睛看着他们
Like looking through the eyes of childhood again.
可是你现在闭上了这双眼睛
And here you are, closing those eyes,
试着不去看仇恨给桑那人造成的影响
trying not to see what bitterness has done to the Son'a,
它把罗佛尔变成一了个疯子同时
how it's turned Ru'afo into a madman.
把你变成一了个懦夫
And you, turned you into a coward,
一个泯灭良心的人
a man who denies his own conscience.
进去
Get in.
一个毫无道德 无视暴行的懦夫
A coward without the moral courage to prevent an atrocity.
你让我恶心！
You offend me!
这就是联邦军官的求饶方法吗？
Is this how a Federation officer pleads for his life?
我不是在为自己求饶
I'm not pleading for my life.
我是在为你求饶
I'm pleading for yours.
还可以回头 加纳
You can still go home, Gal'na.
电脑 关上电梯门
Computer, close turbolift doors.
你要我做的事是不可能的
What you're asking me to do is impossible.
你知道怎么阻止注入器吗？
Do you know how to disable the injector?
得到舰桥上才能操作
I would need to be on the Bridge.
船员都是罗佛尔的心腹 武力没有用
The crew is loyal to Ru'afo. An assault would fail.
也许我们可以调虎离山
Perhaps we can lure him away.
他在哪并不重要
It doesn't matter where he is.
只要他意识到什么不对劲
As soon as he realizes something's happening,
他通过联络器就可以废掉我的指令
he'll override my commands with one word to his comm link.
如果不让他意识不到不对劲…
If he doesn't realize something's happening…
能给我个传送器吗？
Can you get me to a transmitter?
我要联络地面上的数据和胡夫
I need to speak with Data and Worf down on the planet.
让他们帮忙
We'll need their help.
12层
Deck 12.
启动分离协议
Initiate separation protocols.
启动注入器舱
Activating injector assembly.
3分钟后进行分离
Separation in three minutes.
星球上飞来一艘小飞船
A small craft is coming up from the surface.
它正在部署武器
It's powering up its weapons.
- 打开屏幕 - 船上只有一个人 那个机器人
- On screen. - One person aboard. It's the android.
他无关紧要
He's no threat.
- 数据呼叫皮卡特 - 说吧 数据
- Data to Picard. - Go ahead, Data.
我怎样攻击 他们都不管
Captain, they're ignoring my attack.
继续朝护盾发射光速粒子
Keep firing tachyon bursts into the shield grid.
- 胡夫准备好没有？- 是的 长官
- Is Worf in position? - Yes, sir.
他已经准备好了同步传送
He is ready for simultaneous transport.
我们正在接近舰桥 通讯完毕
We're approaching the Bridge. Picard out.
一分钟后进行分离
Separation in one minute.
长官 那首联邦飞船正在攻击我们的护盾
Sir, the Federation ship is creating a disruption in our shield.
如果护盾失灵
If they go out of phase,
我们就没法遮挡热解反应
it'll increase our exposure to the thermolytic reaction.
好吧 摧毁那艘船 重新设置护盾调波
Very well. Destroy that ship. Reset our shield harmonics.
不要延误倒计时
Do not delay the countdown.
数据呼叫皮卡特 他们在切换护盾调波
Data to Picard. They are rotating their shield harmonics.
我要返回地面了 长官
I am attempting to return to the surface, sir.
该死的联邦飞船被打跑了
The Federation ship has been disabled.
二十秒后进行分离放
Separation in 20 seconds.
- 怎么回事？- 不知道
- What is that? - I don't know.
- 系统没有受到影响 - 十秒后进行分离
- The systems don't seem affected. - Separation in 10 seconds.
倒数五秒
Five seconds.
注入器舱已经分离
Injector assembly has separated.
跟模拟情况一模一样
Exactly as the simulations predicted.
重曲辐射量没有任何变化
I'm not showing any change in metaphasic flux levels.
扫描器肯定出问题了
Your scanners must be malfunctioning.
船上所有功能都失灵了
All ship functions are off- line.
如果屏幕还好端端的 别的怎么可能会失灵呢？
How can there be no ship functions if the viewscreen is working?
人造重力很稳定 救生能源…
Artificial gravity is stable. Life support is…
全息飞船
A holodeck.
我们调整护盾的时侯 被传送到全息飞船上来了
We were transported to the holoship when we reset our shields.
我们所看到的全都是假象
Everything we saw was an illusion.
罗阿佛授权△21
Ru'afo, authorization Delta 2-1.
取消所有注入器的指令
Override all interlinked commands to injector assembly one.
无法回应
Unable to comply.
一号注射器舱已经被终止
Injector assembly one has been deactivated.
收集站上所有的注入器子系统都已经确认关闭
All injector subsystems aboard the collector are confirmed off-line.
解除全息船护盾 启动牵引光束
Decloak the holoship and engage a tractor beam.
是 长官
Aye, sir.
船员知道不对劲了
The crew knows something's happened.
我已经封住了舰桥
I've secured the Bridge.
这艘船上有十四个远程传送器
This ship is equipped with 14 long-range transporters.
全部失灵了吗？
Are they all useless?
我们被传送来以后
They must have been locked and secured.
它们肯定被锁定住了
after we were beamed here.
拿出一个
Isolate one.
把命令程序转接到备用处理器上
and re- route its command sequence through the auxiliary processor.
恐怕没什么用 他们已经控制了我们的船
Sir, there's nothing we can do. They already have control of our ship.
我没打算回到我们的船上
I don't plan on going back to our ship.
- 胡夫 摧毁那东西 - 是 长官
- Mr. Worf, destroy that thing. - Aye, sir.
武器系统全都失灵了
Weapons systems have been taken off-line.
船员们更改了舰桥控制权
The crew is re- routing Bridge controls.
船长 收集站上有麻烦
Captain, there is a problem aboard the collector.
启动程序被恢复了
The launch sequence has resumed.
偏正翼护盾被打开了 有人上去了
Collector shields have been raised. Someone's onboard.
是罗阿佛
It's Ru'afo.
从这儿能控制发射程序吗？
Can you override the launch sequence from here?
得有他的访问密码
Not without his access codes.
有自毁程序吗？
Is there a self-destruct?
有 但没有密码
Yes, but without the codes, it would have to be activated.
就只能在收集器的上部控制矩阵启动
at the upper control matrix on the collector.
胡夫 想办法把我传送下去
Mr. Worf, try and find some way to beam through those shields.
你只有手动引爆 仅有两秒钟的时间
You'd have to detonate it manually. There'd only be a two-second delay.
我们只有在离收集站一百米以内
We may be able to transport between the shield generators.
才可以把你传送过去
if we are within 100 meters.
把船靠过去
Take us into position.
守住岗位 中校 你得再把我传送回来
Remain at your post, Commander. I'll need you to beam me back.
正在靠近收集站
We're approaching the collector.
分离前一分钟 制冷缸会开始排气
One minute before separation, you'll see the cryogenic tanks venting.
如果开枪就可能引爆废气
Weapons fire could ignite the exhaust.
两分十五秒后进行分离
Separation in 2 minutes and 15 seconds.
有人闯入 有人闯入
Intruder alert. Intruder alert.
船长！
Captain!
胡夫？
Worf?
收集站上有皮卡特船长的生命迹象
I'm picking up Captain Picard's bio-signature onboard the collector.
- 企业号呼叫皮卡特！- 大副
- Enterprise to Picard! - Number One.
我们正在接近你的位置 需要援助吗？
We're approaching your position. Do you need assistance?
大概一分钟后把我带走
I may need a lift in a minute or so.
我们就来
We're on our way.
一分钟后进行分离
Separation in one minute.
- 报告情况 - 是罗阿佛的船
- Report. - It's Ru'afo's ship!
打开屏幕
On screen.
传感器显示 船上有一百名巴库人和一个克林冈人
Sensors are reading over 100 Ba'ku onboard and one Klingon.
锁定他们的腹部引擎和救生能源
Target their ventral engines and life support.
设定撞击路线
Set a collision course.
住手！
Stop!
罗阿佛 我们太老了 别打了
Ru'afo, we're getting too old for this.
过了今天 对于我们两个来说 这就不再是问题了
After today, that won't be a problem for either of us.
三十秒后进行分离
Separation in 30 seconds.
你真的不怕会点燃废气？
You're really going to risk igniting the exhaust?
好吧 我不怕！
All right, I will!
- 护盾只剩60%了 - 保持航线
- Shields at 60%. - Hold your course.
- 他不会的 - 不 他会的
- He wouldn't. - Yes, he would.
发射！
Now!
准备好船长 我们快到了
Stand by, Captain. We're right around the corner.
对不起 没时间了
Sorry, time's up.
怎么耽搁了 大副？
What kept you, Number One?
联邦议会让我通知你
The Federation Council has asked me to inform you.
先中止巴库人的迁移 他们要认进行高层评估
that the Ba'ku relocation will be halted while they conduct a top-level review.
长官 罗阿佛的飞船在呼叫我们
Sir, Ru'afo's ship is hailing us.
- 打开屏幕 - 打开屏幕
- On screen. - On screen.
船长 桑那船员想跟我们停火
Captain, the Son'a crew would like to negotiate a cease-fire.
可能是因为我们这里
It may have something to do with the fact.
只剩下了三分钟的空气了
that we have three minutes of air left.
企业号上有的是空气 胡夫 准备传送
We have plenty over here, Mr. Worf. Prepare to beam aboard.
等我们远离了重曲辐射
You think when we get away from this metaphasic radiation,
我们的感情会变淡吗？
it'll change the way we feel?
从我遇到你的那天起
Your feelings about her have not changed.
你对她的感情始终如一
since the day I met you, Commander.
这个地方只是让你表现了出来
This place just let them out for a little fresh air.
我希望能有办法让他们回来
I wish there were a way to bring them back home.
问他们
Ask them.
我害怕双方的积怨太深了
I'm afraid there's too much bitterness on both sides.
母子二人
Mother and son.
这是你安排的？
You arranged this?
也许这能成为和解的第一步
I thought it might begin the healing process.
没有你在身边 我该怎么办？
What am I going to do without you?
我也很想留下来
I wish I could stay,
可是联邦现在正处于多事之秋
but these are perilous times for the Federation.
我的一生都在保护家园
I can't abandon it to people who would threaten.
现在当然更不可能置之不理
everything that I've spent a lifetime defending.
我必须得回去
I have to go back,
最起码能让联邦议会的节奏放慢下来
if only to slow things down at the Federation Council.
不过我马上就会有318天的休假
But I have 318 days of shore leave coming and.
我打算申请休假
I intend to use them.
数据？
Data?
我们该走了
It's time to go.
我该回家去了
I have to go home now.
- 再见 - 再见
- Bye. - Bye.
数据先生 希望能再见到你
Mr. Data, I hope we'll see you again.
数据！别忘了 每日都要玩耍一小会儿
Data! Don't forget. You have to have a little fun every day.
好建议
Good advice.
皮卡特呼叫企业号 七人准备上船
Picard to Enterprise. Seven to beam up.
传送
Energize.